Paul Sheldon used to write for a living. Now, he’s writing to stay alive.
Misery is a drama, thriller film directed by Rob Reiner.
After an accident, acclaimed novelist Paul Sheldon is rescued
by a nurse who claims to be his biggest fan.
Her obsession takes a dark turn when she holds him captive in her remote Colorado home and
forces him to write back to life the popular literary character he killed off.
Annie Wilkes, played by Kathy Bates.
Paul Sheldon, played by James Caan.
Buster, played by Richard Farnsworth.
Marcia Sindell, played by Lauren Bacall.
Virginia, played by Frances Sternhagen.
Libby, played by Graham Jarvis.
Misery is a 1990 American psychological horror thriller film directed
by Rob Reiner from a screenplay by William Goldman.
It is based on Stephen King's 1987 novel and stars James Caan as famed novelist Paul
Sheldon, who is held captive by Annie Wilkes (Kathy Bates), an obsessive fan.
The supporting cast includes Frances Sternhagen,
Richard Farnsworth, and Lauren Bacall.
Development on an adaptation of King's novel began after producer Andrew Scheinman
recommended it to Reiner, who recruited Goldman to write the film's screenplay.
Casting for the film was extensive: several actors were considered for the roles of Sheldon and Wilkes
before Caan and Bates were hired; Bates was a stage actress, mostly unknown to film audiences.
Principal photography began in February 1990, with filming
locations including Genoa, Nevada and Los Angeles.
The film's score was composed by Marc Shaiman.
Misery was produced by Castle Rock Entertainment and Nelson Entertainment and was
theatrically released in the United States on November 30, 1990, by Columbia Pictures.
It grossed $61.3 million worldwide and received positive reviews from critics,
with praise for the horror and performances of the leading duo.
Bates's Academy Award for Best Actress win made Misery the only film
based on a novel by King to win an Academy Award.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
nurse, psychopath, colorado, car crash.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.